the purpose of this video is to
illustrate how to use code app sampler
to gener
from a model in the top menu click on
plugins and select sampler here we see a
collection of objects in a mixer that we
can edit you can imagine this mixer as a
hat with pieces of paper in it
I can add objects using the plus button
if I've added too many I can use the
minus button to remove them let's say I
want to simulate a situation of a
carnival duckpond game that has a
collection of rubber ducks in a pond
where 20% of the Ducks are marked on
their belly for a price
if a player picks one of these marked
floating ducks they win a price once the
duck is picked it is returned to the
pond and the booth operator swirls them
around in the pond to mix them up the
booth owners expect about 50 students to
play the game at the carnival
each player pays $1 to pick three Ducks
one at a time with replacement I can
create 10 objects two objects to
represent winning ducks which I will
label as prize an 8 to represent blank
ducks which I will label as no we are
using 10 objects with two labeled prize
to model the situation of having 20%
ducks labeled in the pond
if we click on spinner we can see how
the same distribution from the mixer is
represented in a spinner model these
options appear allow me to choose my
sample size in addition to how many
times I run the simulation the default
option in the sampler is that objects
are chosen with replacement if you're
modeling a scenario that includes
without replacement you can change that
under this options tab also take note of
the hide model option which might be
helpful if you are a teacher and don't
want your students to see the model you
have created I can ask myself the
question after randomly choosing three
ducks what are the chances of winning a
prize for all three I can test this out
by simulating to see about how many
prizes would be won in this scenario
first I'll simulate a round of the game
where one player picks three Ducks
so change the default five items to
three for now I will simulate playing
the game six times so I will collect six
samples and press start you will see
that an object is randomly selected
three times and that this process is
repeated six times in addition a table
automatically starts to populate with
the results of my simulation it is in
the form of a hierarchical table on the
outermost level of the table I see that
so far I've only run one experiment in
the next level I see that I have taken
six samples and in the final level I see
the results of the six samples I took
three values from the first three values
from the second and so on if I click on
sample two for example all three results
from that sample are highlighted I can
now graph the results of my simulation
by creating a graph and dragging value
to the x-axis I can also separate my
results by which sample they belong to
by dragging sample to the y-axis now I'm
going to run the simulation many more
times than to speed up the process I can
change the speed setting to fastest I'm
going to collect 44 more samples
it becomes clear to me that this graph
is not so helpful anymore but I can use
the table to calculate a measure that
may be more helpful to me if I want to
calculate how many prizes students got
and each simulated round of play I can
add an attribute at the sample level by
clicking on this plus sign I click on
the attribute to edit the formula and
count the number of times prize appears
in each sample now let's graph this new
attribute notice that I can change this
kick this attribute to be treated as
categorical and change it into a bar
graph and I notice that none of the
students got three prizes during 50
rounds of play that was a brief
introduction to one way of using the
sampler which is to generate your own
data using a model another way is to
sample data from an existing data set of
population data here I have already
opened a very large dataset of movies
which contains over 5,000 movies and
lots of information on each case or each
movie the data set is from data world's
and was compiled by scraping information
from the online movie database IMDB I'm
going to treat this data set as a
population
even though realistically it is missing
movies let's say I want to take a sample
of these movies to approximate the
average length of movies so I've opened
the sampler again and this time I'm
using the collector tool my data set is
already populated in the collector and
each case is represented by an object I
can also choose other collections here
if they are available
I want to sample 45 movies from my
population so I've changed the 5 to a 45
and I want to do this five times I've
clicked start but sometimes when
sampling from a large collection it may
take a few seconds for cases to be
sampled and for the taped table to
populate now that my five samples of 45
movies each have been taken
I can now graph movie duration and in
order to see what the distribution looks
like for each sample I can separate by
sample I can display the mean and I can
start to see the variability and the
means between samples this is a brief
introduction to how to use the sampler
to collect samples from a dataset